<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>meptrsn</title>
    <link>https://meptrsn.github.io/blog/tags/research/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on meptrsn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://meptrsn.github.io/blog/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Forts, Forts</title>
      <link>https://meptrsn.github.io/blog/post/forts-forts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2016 01:46:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meptrsn.github.io/blog/post/forts-forts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m now doing some research for a presentation next week on Egyptian forts in Nubia. It turns out that this is quite the topic, and the professor I&amp;rsquo;m taking the seminar with is quite interested in it. Specifically, she is heavily involved with excavations at Uronarti, a fortress in southern Lower Nubia. When I told her my choice of topic, she said: &amp;ldquo;going for the professor&amp;rsquo;s research area, that&amp;rsquo;s pretty ballsy.&amp;rdquo; So that bodes well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, it looks like I&amp;rsquo;ll be focusing on the relations between fortresses and their hinterlands, specifically in terms of how cultural exchange occurred between the fortresses (presumably belonging to occupiers) and their surroundings (presumably belonging to the occupied). I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on wrapping my head around the topic as a whole, because my background is more heavily in Assyriology, not in Archaeology. I don&amp;rsquo;t have a great grounding in Nubian studies, and so taking this &lt;em&gt;graduate&lt;/em&gt; seminar has been a bit of a learning experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh well. At least there&amp;rsquo;s wine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research issues</title>
      <link>https://meptrsn.github.io/blog/post/Research-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 18:57:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meptrsn.github.io/blog/post/Research-issues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a bit hard-going with my research work for my thesis. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on building a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/45909007_Granular_Flows_in_Split-Bottom_Geometries&#34;&gt;split-bottom flow cell&lt;/a&gt; for granular flow research; unfortunately, it&amp;rsquo;s been rather difficult to install the glass beads on the sides of the walls with epoxy. Due to the curved surface, it&amp;rsquo;s sort of tricky to coat the walls evenly. In addition, it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to get the cell walls (a polycarbonate cylinder) to seat properly due to splotches of epoxy that thicken the walls in some places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving forward, I&amp;rsquo;ll be working on getting the cell fully assembled, and then installing the lighting and camera for image capture. I&amp;rsquo;ll be using digital image correlation (DIC) to extract velocity fields from the image data, and getting some good data from my lab setup will be a big step forward.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>