<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post-rsses on meptrsn</title>
    <link>https://meptrsn.github.io/blog/post/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post-rsses on meptrsn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 20:35:11 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://meptrsn.github.io/blog/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>November Update</title>
      <link>https://meptrsn.github.io/blog/post/november_update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 20:35:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meptrsn.github.io/blog/post/november_update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;November comes slowly to an end, and with it, the Yuletide season quickly approaches. I taught at &lt;a href=&#34;https://esp.mit.edu/learn/Splash/index.html&#34;&gt;Splash (MIT&amp;rsquo;s volunteer-taught cavalcade of classes for high-schoolers)&lt;/a&gt; this year, teaching two courses: a class on quickly making ad hoc tabletop scenarios (you can find my course notes &lt;a href=&#34;../../fun.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), and a workshop on cuneiform. Both went quit well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanksgiving also went well; I enjoyed a time at a Professor&amp;rsquo;s house, and went with several friends, bringing three pies, cranberry sauce, and creamed onions. A wonderful time was had by all. I have gone to this Professor&amp;rsquo;s house each year, and at this point, I&amp;rsquo;m the primary pie-maker. We brought apple, pumpkin, and chocolate pecan pies (recipes for the latter &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kingarthurflour.com/recipes/pumpkin-pie-recipe&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.sciencemag.org/pipeline/archives/2010/11/24/holiday_organic_synthesis_chocolate_pecan_pie&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), using my grandmother&amp;rsquo;s crust recipe. I made a small modification to the crust, which calls for 1 teaspoon of vinegar - I replaced this with a half-teaspoon of vinegar and a half-teaspoon of calvados - the alcohol makes the crust easier to roll out, and both ingredients suppress gluten formation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On to other items: In the course of researching for my Splash class, I did a lot of reading and found useful in particular articles from &lt;a href=&#34;http://thealexandrian.net/&#34;&gt;The Alexandrian&lt;/a&gt;, a website which has many useful articles relating to scenario design, gamemastering, and tabletop games in general. A good find, and I heartily recommend it. In any case, this website led me to discover a much wider world of tabletop games, many of which I would definitely like to try out, in particular &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technoirrpg.com/&#34;&gt;Technoir&lt;/a&gt;, a cyberpunk game of &amp;ldquo;high-tech, hardboiled roleplaying.&amp;rdquo; It uses a cool resolution system, and has some nice scenario design concepts at its heart that make it an attractive option for ad hoc play. I also enjoyed the post about &lt;a href=&#34;http://thealexandrian.net/wordpress/36625/roleplaying-games/check-this-out-city-generators&#34;&gt;dice drop generators for cities&lt;/a&gt; which connected me to some resources I&amp;rsquo;d never seen before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, on to December, and soon, break. I have many final projects to complete before the sun sets on this semester, but when they&amp;rsquo;re done, oh, how lovely the respite will be.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>https://meptrsn.github.io/blog/post/First-Post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 04:48:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meptrsn.github.io/blog/post/First-Post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have just recently set up this blog, mainly as a sort of matter of course, but hopefully it will eventually act as a way to record thoughts and ideas, as well as a place to document projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>